Rahul Rathod

Lead Software Engineer | iOS Developer

Quality-oriented, motivated individual professional committed in bringing out the best in the organization using my skills and 9+ years of experience in creating and maintaining iOS native applications. I am looking for an opportunity which will utilize my expertise of iOS application development and delivering the best quality products within strict timelines. I have strong will to work in an organization which offers growth opportunities and allows me to utilize my skills and experience.

raaulc@outlook.com

+91 - 9892378009



Bengaluru, India

in linkedin.com/in/raaulc

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer | iOS Developer M&S (TCS - Tata Consultancy Services)

Bengaluru, India

- Responsible for the development, testing, and maintenance of native SDKs on iOS platform, their respective OS versions, and devices.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Performing unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- Working on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Maintaining code quality, organization, and automatization.
- Conducting scrum meetings, assigning task to team members and supervising their work.

Lead Software Engineer BESTBUY (TCS - Tata Consultancy Services)

Chennai India

- Worked with product owners and management to chart out the product roadmap for upcoming sprints.
- Responsible for the account of technical debt, code smells and managed the sprint deliveries
- Monitored App performance using performance monitoring and crashlytics.
- Worked on refactoring old deprecated code and any components that have come up for development.
- Ensured good architectural practices, regular code-review, the right tool for the job, and tracked and handled potential problem areas in the code.
- Worked on unit testing and UI Automation test suites.

Technical Lead Capgemini

06/2012 - 09/2016

Mumhai India

- Coordinated with customer for application features and requirements,
- Designed and developed mobile applications for Apple's iOS platform for various clients i.e. - 3M, ING, Dako, St. Jose Medical.
- Ensured quality and performance of the application to specifications.
- Identified potential problems and resolved critical technical issues.
- Triaged defects and fixed application bugs for best quality of the product.
- Published application on App Store.

Assistant Software Engineer

Persource

- Worked on various event based product mobile applications for US Govt, Yahoo, Aspen, Sundance Film Festival and many more.
- Created end to end 15+ iOS applications.
- Part of the core team and responsible for design and development.

Jr. iOS Developer **BYPT**

09/2010 - 04/2011

Ahmedabad, India

- Worked on developing various live scoring apps for football leagues across the
- Designed the UI for the application as per requirements.
- Performed unit testing and delivered the application time.

CORE SKILLS



GENERAL SKILLS



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering -**Electronics & Communications** Dharmsinh Desai University

08/2005 - 05/2009 Gujarat, India

ACHIEVEMENTS

Recognized with "Take a Bow" award in BESTBUY.

Received "Star Award of the month" in M&S.

Achieved "Pat on the Back" award in iGATE Technologies.

TRAININGS

SwiftUI & Combine

IIT - Madras

Protocol Oriented Swift Programming TCS, Chennai